<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<article>
    <metadata/>
    <speedread>
        <para>Value added tax (VAT) is an EU tax levied by Customs &amp; Excise on supplies for a consideration made by
            a taxable person in the UK in the course or furtherance of a business.
        </para>
        <para>Taxable person. A taxable person is an individual, limited company or other entity which is registered, or
            required to be registered for VAT. The threshold for compulsory registration is a historical annual turnover
            of £50,000. However, a taxpayer may choose to register voluntarily.
        </para>
        <para>Input and output tax. VAT is borne economically by the ultimate consumer of the goods or services supplied
            but is the liability of the person making the supply. Suppliers generally deduct an amount equal to the VAT
            on the supplies to them (input tax) from the VAT which they charge on onward supplies (output tax) and pay
            the difference to Customs. At each stage of the supply chain the net VAT paid is on the value added at that
            stage.
        </para>
        <para>Categories. Supplies are divided into three main categories: standard rated supplies, zero rated supplies
            and exempt supplies. Most supplies are standard rated and therefore subject to VAT at the standard rate of
            17.5%. Zero rated supplies do not require the supplier to charge VAT. They comprise a number of socially
            beneficial items such as new houses, however, unlike an exempt supply a zero rated supply is a taxable
            supply chargeable at a zero rate. Suppliers are not required to account for output tax on exempt supplies
            but are unable to recover the input tax on those supplies which they receive that are attributable to the
            exempt supplies. Exempt supplies include financial services and certain property transactions.
        </para>
        <para>Supplies. VAT legislation does not exhaustively define the term supply but it is very broad in its scope.
            The distinction as to whether a supply is one of goods or services is important as different rules apply to
            the time and place of supply. Also the treatment of the international supply of goods and services is
            different.
        </para>
        <para>VAT is charged at the value of a supply. The consideration agreed on is always inclusive of VAT unless the
            contrary is specified.
        </para>
        <para>There are a number of transactions that are treated as neither a supply of goods nor of services and are
            therefore outside the scope of VAT. These include the transfer of a business as a going concern, services of
            employees, most supplies between members of a VAT group, dividends and transactions between divisions of the
            same corporate body.
        </para>
        <para>Group registration. Two or more companies can be registered as a group for VAT purposes if one controls
            the others or some person controls all of them and each company either is resident in the UK for VAT
            purposes or has an established place of business in the UK. The representative group member is responsible
            for completing the VAT returns of the whole group and is principally liable for the whole group’s VAT. One
            of the main advantages of group registration is that transactions between members of a group are ignored for
            VAT purposes.
        </para>
    </speedread>
    <fulltext>
        <section1>
            <para>
                <graphic fileref="binaryContent.jsp?item=835914"/>
            </para>
            <para>Value added tax (VAT), alone among UK taxes, is an EU tax. It is levied by HM Customs &amp; Excise on
                supplies for a consideration made by a "taxable person" in the UK in the course or furtherance of a
                business.
            </para>
            <para>The broad framework of VAT is contained in a series of EC Directives, the principal one of which is
                the EC Sixth Directive (<emphasis role="italic">77/388/EEC</emphasis>). The primary UK legislation on
                VAT is the Value Added Tax Act 1994 (VATA 1994). This provides the framework of the tax but much of the
                detail is found in statutory instruments, either in the form of orders made by the Treasury or
                regulations made by Customs &amp; Excise. Where UK legislation is clearly in conflict with EC law, EC
                law prevails.
            </para>
            <section2>
                <title>Taxable person</title>
                <para>A "taxable person" is an individual, limited company or other entity which is registered, or
                    required to be registered, for VAT with Customs &amp; Excise. The threshold for compulsory
                    registration is an historical annual turnover of £50,000. A person must also register if he expects
                    his turnover in the next 30 days to exceed £50,000. However, a tax payer can choose to register if
                    he has a taxable turnover below £50,000. This is known as voluntary registration.
                </para>
            </section2>
            <section2>
                <title>Input and output tax</title>
                <para>The essence of VAT is that it should be borne economically by the ultimate consumer of the goods
                    or services supplied. Traders may generally deduct an amount equal to the VAT on supplies to them (
                    <emphasis role="bold">
                        <emphasis role="italic">input tax</emphasis>
                    </emphasis>
                    ) from the VAT which they charge on supplies (
                    <emphasis role="bold">
                        <emphasis role="italic">output tax</emphasis>
                    </emphasis>
                    ), and only pay the difference to Customs &amp; Excise. Thus at each stage of the
                    <emphasis role="bold">
                        <emphasis role="italic">supply chain</emphasis>
                    </emphasis>
                    the net VAT paid is on the value added at that stage.
                </para>
                <para>Although the tax is borne ultimately by the consumer, it is the supplier that has to pay the VAT
                    chargeable on the supply to Customs &amp; Excise as VAT is a liability of the person making the
                    supply (<emphasis role="italic">section 1(2), VATA 1994</emphasis>). The supplier normally passes
                    that liability on to his customer by identifying the price that he would have charged for his supply
                    in the absence of VAT and increasing that price by an amount equal to the VAT that is in fact
                    chargeable on the supply. A supplier's liability to pay VAT is thus simply another expense that a
                    supplier should take into account when charging for goods. The only difference from other expenses
                    is that, by convention, the additional amount paid by the recipient of the supply in respect of VAT
                    is separately delineated.
                </para>
                <para>VAT is therefore not a charge on the consumer as such, nor is the consumer "paying VAT"; he is
                    paying additional consideration for the supply equal to the VAT liability of the supplier. This is
                    fundamental to understanding how VAT works.
                </para>
                <para>VAT clauses in documents that refer to consideration being "exclusive of VAT" are therefore
                    misconceived. What they should say is that the consideration is "exclusive of any amount arising in
                    respect of VAT" on the supply in question and that the purchaser "will pay a sum equal to such
                    amount to the vendor by way of additional consideration".
                </para>
            </section2>
            <section2>
                <title>Calculation and rates</title>
                <para>Supplies are divided into three main categories for VAT purposes:</para>
                <itemizedlist>
                    <listitem>
                        <para>Standard rated supplies.</para>
                    </listitem>
                    <listitem>
                        <para>Zero rated supplies.</para>
                    </listitem>
                    <listitem>
                        <para>Exempt supplies.</para>
                    </listitem>
                </itemizedlist>
                <para>A reduced rate of 5% applies to supplies of fuel and power for domestic and certain other
                    qualifying uses.
                </para>
                <para>
                    <emphasis role="bold">Standard rated supplies.</emphasis>
                    Most supplies are subject to VAT at the standard rate of 17.5%. In its simplest form (where each
                    person in the supply chain apart from the ultimate consumer is fully taxable at the standard rate),
                    the tax operates so as to cause each person in the supply chain (other than the end user) to account
                    to Customs &amp; Excise for VAT on the value which that person adds to the goods or services in the
                    chain, whilst the end user bears the cost of all the VAT previously accounted for.
                </para>
                <para>The machinery devised to achieve this end is that each person in the supply chain pays to its
                    suppliers input tax which is equal to the VAT on the gross value of the supplies it receives and
                    accounts to Customs &amp; Excise for the output tax on the gross value of the supplies it makes. The
                    input tax is wholly credited against the output tax, leaving the person with an overall liability to
                    VAT which is equal to 17.5% of the value added by that person.
                </para>
                <para>For example, suppose that A supplies parts to B and B uses those parts to make machinery which it
                    then sells to C. Suppose that the parts are sold to B for £100 plus an amount in respect of VAT of
                    £17.50 and that B then sells the machinery to C for £200 plus an amount in respect of VAT of £35. A
                    will account to Customs &amp; Excise for output tax of £17.50 in respect of its supply to B. B will
                    account for output tax of £35 in respect of its supply to C but will reclaim input tax of £17.50
                    from Customs &amp; Excise. The net liability of B in respect of this transaction is therefore
                    £17.50. If C is not registered for VAT, it will have paid £235 to B for the machinery, which
                    includes £35 of irrecoverable input tax. This £35 was accounted for to Customs &amp; Excise as to
                    £17.50 by B and £17.50 by A (<emphasis role="italic">see inset box "A standard rated
                        supply"</emphasis>).
                </para>
                <para>
                    <emphasis role="bold">Zero rated supplies.</emphasis>
                    Zero rated supplies do not require the supplier to charge VAT. They comprise a number of socially
                    beneficial items, such as new houses, children's clothing, books, periodicals and newspapers (
                    <emphasis role="italic">Schedule 8, VATA 1994</emphasis>).
                </para>
                <para>However, unlike an exempt supply, a zero rated supply is a taxable supply. It merely happens to be
                    chargeable at a zero rate. A maker of zero rated supplies is able to recover all of the input tax
                    which is attributable to his zero rated supplies (because such supplies are taxable) but is not
                    required to account for output tax on those supplies (because of the zero rate). Thus, in economic
                    terms, a zero rated supply breaks the accumulation of tax on added value which generally builds up
                    in the supply chain.
                </para>
                <para>For example, suppose that A supplies machinery to B, a clothes supplier, for £100 plus £17.50 in
                    respect of VAT. B uses the machinery to manufacture children's clothes which it wishes to sell to C
                    at a price which covers the cost of the machinery plus £100. The supply of children's clothes is
                    zero rated for VAT purposes. Accordingly, B will be able to recover the £17.50 of input tax incurred
                    on the acquisition of the machinery but will not be obliged to account for any output tax in respect
                    of the supply of the children's clothes to C. The effect of this is that, in setting its prices for
                    C, B will take into account only £100 of machinery costs as B will have recovered an amount equal to
                    the aggregate of the VAT accounted for by A. C will therefore only be charged £200 for the clothes (
                    <emphasis role="italic">see inset box "A zero rated supply"</emphasis>).
                </para>
                <para>
                    <emphasis role="bold">Exempt supplies.</emphasis>
                    Where a person makes exempt supplies, he is treated in that respect as if he were the ultimate
                    consumer . He is not required to account for output tax on his exempt supplies but he is unable to
                    recover the input tax on those supplies which he has received that are attributable to his exempt
                    supplies. In economic terms, this results in the ultimate consumer bearing the cost of value added
                    by the standard rated suppliers earlier in the supply chain but not the cost of value added by the
                    person making the exempt supply. Exempt supplies include financial services (for example, the sale
                    of securities, lending money, underwriting, broking and insurance) and certain transactions in land
                    and buildings (<emphasis role="italic">Schedule 9, VATA 1994</emphasis>).
                </para>
                <para>For example, suppose that A supplies machinery to B, a bank, for £100 plus £17.50 in respect of
                    VAT. B uses the machinery for the purposes of financial services supplied to C for which he wishes
                    to recover the cost of the machinery plus £100. As the supply of financial services is an exempt
                    supply, B will not be obliged to account for output tax in respect of supplies made to C. As,
                    however, the machinery is being used for the purposes of making exempt supplies, B is not able to
                    recover the input tax of £17.50 incurred on the acquisition of the machinery, and so the price
                    charged by B to C will have to take into account this additional cost to B. C will therefore be
                    charged £217.50 (<emphasis role="italic">see inset box "An exempt supply"</emphasis>). Failure by B
                    to take into account this additional VAT cost will reduce B's profits in the same way that failure
                    to take into account any other business expense would do so.
                </para>
                <para>If B is not making wholly exempt supplies, but rather is using the machinery to make both standard
                    rated and exempt supplies, B will be able to recover a proportion of the input tax incurred on the
                    acquisition of the machinery and so the cost taken into account by B as part of its overheads will
                    be reduced.
                </para>
            </section2>
            <section2>
                <title>Supply of goods and services</title>
                <para>The VAT legislation does not exhaustively define the term "supply" but it is very broad in its
                    scope. It is defined to include circumstances in which, for example, a taxable person takes goods
                    out of a business for private use, borrows goods for private use or puts his services to private
                    use. Therefore, where a solicitor who is a taxable person does his own house conveyancing and uses
                    his office staff and facilities for this purpose, he must account for VAT on the cost.
                </para>
                <para>The distinction as to whether a supply is one of goods or services is important as different rules
                    apply to the time and place of supply. Also the treatment of the international supply of goods and
                    services is different (<emphasis role="italic">see "Place of supply" and "Time of supply"
                        below</emphasis>).
                </para>
                <para>"Goods" include capital assets and stock in trade. A "service" for this purpose is not only the
                    provision of advice or skills to someone but also any other thing that is not a supply of goods but
                    is done for consideration (such as the making of a loan, the sale or issue of a share or the waiver
                    of a legal right) (<emphasis role="italic">section 5(2), VATA 1994</emphasis>). A transaction in
                    land may be either a supply of goods or services, depending on the nature of the interest in land
                    that is the subject of the transaction.
                </para>
            </section2>
            <section2>
                <title>Place of supply</title>
                <para>To be within the charge to UK VAT, a supply must be made in the UK. Supplies made outside the UK
                    are outside the scope of UK VAT (although they may be liable to VAT in another country). It is
                    therefore important to establish where a particular supply is made. Separate rules apply to the
                    supply of goods and services:
                </para>
                <para>
                    <emphasis role="bold">Goods.</emphasis>
                    If goods are outside the UK, the supply is treated as made outside the UK. If goods are inside the
                    UK, the supply is treated as made in the UK.
                </para>
                <para>If the supply involves the removal of goods from the UK they are treated as supplied in the UK. If
                    the supply involves the removal of goods to the UK they are to be treated as supplied outside the
                    UK.
                </para>
                <para>Therefore, exports are supplies of goods which are within the scope of VAT, whereas imports are
                    supplies which are outside the scope of VAT, at least in relation to the charge to VAT on taxable
                    supplies. The importer is however likely to be liable to account for VAT on the supply (<emphasis
                            role="italic">see below</emphasis>).
                </para>
                <para>Thus, the whole issue turns solely on the physical location of the goods themselves. It does not
                    matter where either party to the supply has its main business presence. For example, if the goods
                    that form the subject matter of the supply are held somewhere in the UK, the place of supply is in
                    the UK even if neither the maker of the supply nor the recipient have any form of business
                    establishment or other business presence in the UK.
                </para>
                <para>
                    <emphasis role="bold">Services.</emphasis>
                    The basic rule is that a supply of services is treated as made in the country where the supplier
                    himself "belongs" for VAT purposes (<emphasis role="italic">see inset box "Meaning of
                    "belongs""</emphasis>). There are however a number of important exceptions to this basic rule (
                    <emphasis role="italic">VAT (Place of Supply of Services) Order 1992 SI 3121</emphasis>) (the
                    Order). The main exceptions are:
                </para>
                <itemizedlist>
                    <listitem>
                        <para>Where a supply of services relates to land, it is treated as made in the country where the
                            land in connection with which the supply is made is itself situated; it does not matter
                            where either party to the supply "belongs".
                        </para>
                    </listitem>
                    <listitem>
                        <para>Where a supply of services consists of any services set out in Article 15 of the Order
                            (which include, for example, conferences, sporting and entertainment services), it is
                            treated as made in the country where the services themselves are physically carried out; it
                            does not matter where either party to the supply belongs (<emphasis role="italic">see inset
                                box "Article 15 services"</emphasis>).
                        </para>
                    </listitem>
                    <listitem>
                        <para>Where a person belonging in the UK makes a supply of any services falling within
                            paragraphs (i)-(viii) of Schedule 5 of the VATA 1994 (which include legal, banking and
                            financial services) to a person who belongs outside the UK and in a country (other than the
                            Isle of Man) that is not an EU member state, the supply is treated as made in the country
                            where the recipient "belongs" and is accordingly outside the scope of UK VAT (<emphasis
                                    role="italic">see inset box "Schedule 5 services"</emphasis>).
                        </para>
                    </listitem>
                    <listitem>
                        <para>Where a person belonging in the UK makes a supply of any Schedule 5 services to a person
                            who "belongs" outside the UK but in a country that is another EU member state, the supply is
                            treated as made in the member state where the recipient belongs, and is accordingly outside
                            the scope of UK VAT if, and only if:
                        </para>
                        <itemizedlist>
                            <listitem>
                                <para>the recipient receives the supply for the purpose of a business carried on by him;
                                    and
                                </para>
                            </listitem>
                            <listitem>
                                <para>the recipient is registered for the local equivalent of VAT in the member state in
                                    which he belongs.
                                </para>
                            </listitem>
                        </itemizedlist>
                        <?Pub Caret1?>
                    </listitem>
                </itemizedlist>
            </section2>
            <section2>
                <title>Time of supply</title>
                <para>The time at which a supply of goods or services takes place is called the tax point. It is a
                    significant date. A supplier becomes liable to VAT by reference to the time of supply. The timing of
                    credit for input tax is also referable to the time of supply.
                </para>
                <para>There are different rules for goods and services all of which can be displaced by prior issue of a
                    VAT invoice or payment.
                </para>
                <para>
                    <emphasis role="bold">Goods.</emphasis>
                    There are three basic rules relating to goods:
                </para>
                <itemizedlist>
                    <listitem>
                        <para>If the goods are to be removed, the tax point is the time of removal (that is, the date
                            when they are sent to the customer or he takes them away).
                        </para>
                    </listitem>
                    <listitem>
                        <para>If the goods are not to be removed (for example, because they are built on site) the tax
                            point is when they are made available to the recipient. For example, on a sale of the
                            freehold in a building, the freehold is normally "made available" on legal completion.
                        </para>
                    </listitem>
                    <listitem>
                        <para>If the goods are removed, but at the time of removal it is unclear whether a supply will
                            actually take place (because they are on approval or subject to sale or return), the supply
                            is treated as taking place when it becomes clear that a supply has taken place or, if
                            sooner, twelve months after the removal.
                        </para>
                    </listitem>
                </itemizedlist>
                <para>
                    <emphasis role="bold">Services.</emphasis>
                    Services are treated as taking place at the time they are performed. This seems to mean at the time
                    when they are completed (subject to some special provisions relating to continuous supplies, such as
                    construction work or the leasing of land or goods, where the consideration is payable periodically).
                </para>
                <para>
                    <emphasis role="bold">Exceptions.</emphasis>
                    The above rules relating to goods and services can be displaced by one of two events occurring
                    before the date which would otherwise be the tax point:
                </para>
                <itemizedlist>
                    <listitem>
                        <para>VAT invoice. The issue of a VAT invoice for a standard rated supply. Where this occurs,
                            the supply is treated as taking place at the time of the tax invoice.
                        </para>
                    </listitem>
                    <listitem>
                        <para>Payment. If a payment is received in respect of a supply of any type, the supply is to be
                            treated as taking place when payment is received.
                        </para>
                    </listitem>
                    <listitem>
                        <para>In both of the above cases, the supply is treated as taking place only to the extent of
                            the amount invoiced or payment received.
                        </para>
                    </listitem>
                    <listitem>
                        <para>If a VAT invoice is issued within 14 days after the time when a standard rated supply
                            would otherwise be treated as taking place, the date of the VAT invoice is substituted for
                            the date which would otherwise have been the tax point.
                        </para>
                    </listitem>
                </itemizedlist>
            </section2>
            <section2>
                <title>Value of supply</title>
                <para>VAT is charged on the value of a supply. Where the only consideration for a supply is money, the
                    value of the supply is the amount which, once the tax charged on the supply is added to it, equals
                    the consideration for the supply (<emphasis role="italic">section 19(2), VATA 1994</emphasis>).
                </para>
                <para>The consideration agreed on is therefore inclusive of VAT unless the contrary is so specified.
                    This is a fundamental point. If a supplier wants a customer to pay him an amount that will cover the
                    supplier's liability to VAT on the supply, he must ensure that the contract specifically requires
                    that amount to be paid.
                </para>
                <para>Where the consideration for a supply does not consist wholly of money, the value of the supply is
                    taken as such amount of money as, with the addition of VAT chargeable, is equivalent to that
                    consideration (<emphasis role="italic">section 19(3), VATA 1994</emphasis>). There are special rules
                    relating to discounts, transactions between connected persons and values expressed in foreign
                    currencies.
                </para>
            </section2>
            <section2>
                <title>Supplies outside the scope of VAT</title>
                <para>There are a number of transactions that are treated as neither a supply of goods nor of services
                    and are therefore outside the scope of VAT. These include:
                </para>
                <itemizedlist>
                    <listitem>
                        <para>The transfer of a business as a going concern. This applies to the sale of the whole of a
                            business or of part of a business that is capable of separate operation (<emphasis
                                    role="italic">Article 5, Value Added Tax (Special Provisions) Order 1995, SI
                                1995/1268</emphasis>).
                        </para>
                    </listitem>
                    <listitem>
                        <para>Most supplies between members of a VAT group (<emphasis role="italic">see "Group
                            registration" below</emphasis>).
                        </para>
                    </listitem>
                    <listitem>
                        <para>Services of employees. (The services of a self-employed person are within the scope of
                            VAT.)
                        </para>
                    </listitem>
                    <listitem>
                        <para>Dividends.</para>
                    </listitem>
                    <listitem>
                        <para>Transactions between divisions of the same corporate body.</para>
                    </listitem>
                    <listitem>
                        <para>Financial, legal or accountancy advice given to a client that is supplied either to a
                            client belonging in, and registered for VAT in, another EU member state who receives the
                            advice for business purposes or to a client who belongs outside the EU (<emphasis
                                    role="italic">Schedule 5, VATA 1994</emphasis>).
                        </para>
                    </listitem>
                    <listitem>
                        <para>Services provided by an agent acting in his own name to a purchaser of goods where the
                            consideration for the services is taken into account in calculating the price at which the
                            agent obtained the goods (<emphasis role="italic">Article 9, Value Added Tax (Special
                                Provisions) Order 1995, SI 1995/1268</emphasis>).
                        </para>
                    </listitem>
                </itemizedlist>
                <para>Where services are outside the scope of VAT, sometimes the supplier can obtain a refund of related
                    input tax (<emphasis role="italic">see inset box "Corporate transactions"</emphasis>).
                </para>
            </section2>
            <section2>
                <title>Imports and exports</title>
                <para>Different rules apply for goods and services which are imported to or exported from the UK.</para>
                <para>
                    <emphasis role="bold">Goods.</emphasis>
                    Goods imported from a country outside the EU are subject to VAT if the same goods supplied in the UK
                    by a registered trader would be subject to VAT. The rate is the same as would apply to a UK supply.
                </para>
                <para>An importer of goods from outside the EU must calculate and pay VAT on the value of goods imported
                    (the price plus packaging, freight as far as the first destination in the EU, insurance, commission
                    and customs and excise duties). This will be treated as input tax in his hands. Exports of goods
                    outside the EU are generally zero rated.
                </para>
                <para>
                    <emphasis role="bold">Services.</emphasis>
                    If standard rated services are supplied to a person belonging in the UK by a trader that belongs
                    outside the UK (inside or outside the EU), VAT may be charged in one of two ways:
                </para>
                <itemizedlist>
                    <listitem>
                        <para>Under the reverse charge system, certain supplies (including those in paragraphs
                            (i)-(viii) of Schedule 5 of the VATA 1994 (<emphasis role="italic">see inset box " Schedule
                                5 services"</emphasis>)) are treated as made by the UK recipient who must therefore pay
                            VAT on their value. This will be treated as input tax in his hands. Correspondingly, some
                            services supplied by UK traders to overseas customers are not subject to UK VAT because they
                            will be treated as supplied in the country of the recipient.
                        </para>
                    </listitem>
                    <listitem>
                        <para>VAT may have to be charged by the supplier in the ordinary way if he is registered.</para>
                    </listitem>
                </itemizedlist>
            </section2>
            <section2>
                <title>Goods sold within the EU</title>
                <para>The general approach for goods sold within the EU is:</para>
                <itemizedlist>
                    <listitem>
                        <para>If the goods are sold between traders that are VAT registered, the supplier shows the
                            customer's state code and VAT registration number on the invoice and zero rates the supply.
                            The customer must pay VAT at his country's rate on the supply to him.
                        </para>
                    </listitem>
                    <listitem>
                        <para>On a supply to an unregistered customer, the supplier applies VAT (at his own country's
                            rate) in the same way that he would for a sale in his own country.
                        </para>
                    </listitem>
                    <listitem>
                        <para>If a supplier makes substantial sales to unregistered buyers in one country, for example,
                            by mail order, he may have to register in that country and apply its VAT rate.
                        </para>
                    </listitem>
                </itemizedlist>
                <para>There are exceptions to these rules affecting particular goods including motor vehicles, ships and
                    aircraft.
                </para>
            </section2>
            <section2>
                <title>Group registration</title>
                <para>Two or more companies can be registered as a group for VAT purposes if one controls the others or
                    some person (not necessarily a company itself) controls all of them and each company either is
                    resident in the UK for VAT purposes or has an established place of business in the UK.
                </para>
                <para>The test of control is that which applies in section 736 of the Companies Act 1985 so that one
                    company is a subsidiary of another, if the other company:
                </para>
                <itemizedlist>
                    <listitem>
                        <para>Holds a majority of the voting rights in it; or</para>
                    </listitem>
                    <listitem>
                        <para>Is a member of it and has the right to appoint or remove a majority of its board of
                            directors; or
                        </para>
                    </listitem>
                    <listitem>
                        <para>Is a member of it and controls alone, pursuant to an agreement with other shareholders or
                            members, a majority of the voting rights in it.
                        </para>
                    </listitem>
                    <listitem>
                        <para>A group has to be registered as a group and only extends to companies that have been
                            registered as members of it. When a group is in existence, one member, called the
                            representative member, is responsible for completing the VAT returns of the whole group and
                            is principally liable for the whole group's VAT. The main consequences of group registration
                            are:
                        </para>
                    </listitem>
                    <listitem>
                        <para>Transactions between members of a group are completely ignored for VAT purposes,
                            regardless of whether they would otherwise have been taxable or exempt supplies.
                        </para>
                    </listitem>
                    <listitem>
                        <para>All supplies made to or by any member of a VAT group are treated as made to or by the
                            representative member alone.
                        </para>
                    </listitem>
                    <listitem>
                        <para>All members are jointly and severally liable for any VAT due from the representative
                            member. In other words, each member of the group is contingently liable to pay the tax
                            chargeable on the supplies made by the whole group, and not merely on what would have been
                            its own supplies had it been separately registered.
                        </para>
                    </listitem>
                </itemizedlist>
                <para>Customs &amp; Excise issued a consultative document in June 1998 containing a proposal that
                    companies that are exempt or partially exempt (that is, cannot recover all VAT charged to them)
                    should not be eligible for inclusion in a VAT group. In general, this is an unwelcome proposal for
                    exempt or partially exempt businesses, particularly those businesses that will receive taxable
                    supplies from associated companies if excluded from the VAT group.
                </para>
            </section2>
            <section2>
                <title>VAT returns</title>
                <para>Once a person is registered, it must account for VAT on the output of goods or services. It can
                    credit any input tax on goods or services wholly used by him in making taxable supplies (that is,
                    non-exempt supplies). The business is allocated a VAT number and must make returns to Customs &amp;
                    Excise. Generally this is done every three months.
                </para>
                <para>
                    <emphasis role="italic">Melissa Hardee is a partner in and Mike Boutell a solicitor with Cameron
                        McKenna. Some of the text and diagrams are adapted from excerpts of the PLC VAT in Property
                        Transactions Practice Manual by Tony Beare of Slaughter and May.
                    </emphasis>
                </para>
            </section2>
        </section1>
        <section1>
            <title>Article 15 services</title>
            <para>Where a supply of services consists of any services set out in Article 15 of the VAT (Place of Supply
                of Services) Order 1992, it is treated as made in the country where the services themselves are
                physically carried out; it does not matter where either party to the supply belongs. Services specified
                in Article 15 of the Order are:
            </para>
            <itemizedlist>
                <listitem>
                    <para>Cultural, artistic, sporting, scientific, educational or entertainment services.</para>
                </listitem>
                <listitem>
                    <para>Services relating to exhibitions, conferences or meetings.</para>
                </listitem>
                <listitem>
                    <para>Services ancillary to, including those of organising, any supply of a description within the
                        above two paragraphs.
                    </para>
                </listitem>
                <listitem>
                    <para>The valuation of, or work carried out on, any goods.</para>
                </listitem>
            </itemizedlist>
        </section1>
        <section1>
            <title>Meaning of "belongs"</title>
            <para>A supplier or recipient "belongs" in a particular country if he has a business establishment or some
                fixed establishment in that country and no such establishment in any other country.
            </para>
            <para>If the supplier or recipient has no business establishment or other fixed establishment in any
                country, he belongs in the country where he has his usual place of residence.
            </para>
            <para>The supplier of services is to be treated as belonging in the country in which is situated his
                establishment which is "most directly concerned with the supply".
            </para>
            <para>The recipient of services is to be treated as belonging in the country in which is situated his
                establishment "at which, or for the purposes of which, the services are most directly used or to be
                used".
            </para>
        </section1>
        <section1>
            <title>Schedule 5 services</title>
            <para>Services falling within paragraphs (i)-(viii), Schedule 5, VATA 1994 are:</para>
            <itemizedlist>
                <listitem>
                    <para>(i) Transfers and assignments of copyright, patents, licences, trademarks and similar
                        rights.
                    </para>
                </listitem>
                <listitem>
                    <para>(ii) Advertising services.</para>
                </listitem>
                <listitem>
                    <para>(iii) Services of consultants, engineers, consultancy bureaux, lawyers, accountants and other
                        similar services; data processing and provision of information (but excluding from any services
                        relating to land).
                    </para>
                </listitem>
                <listitem>
                    <para>(iv) Acceptance of any obligation to refrain from pursuing or exercising, in whole or part,
                        any business activity or any rights as referred to in paragraph (i) above.
                    </para>
                </listitem>
                <listitem>
                    <para>(v) Banking, financial and insurance services (including reinsurance, but not including the
                        provision of safe deposit facilities).
                    </para>
                </listitem>
                <listitem>
                    <para>(vi) The supply of staff.</para>
                </listitem>
                <listitem>
                    <para>(vii) The letting on hire of goods other than means of transport.</para>
                </listitem>
                <listitem>
                    <para>(viii) The services rendered by one person to another in procuring for the other any of the
                        services mentioned in paragraphs (i) to (vii) above.
                    </para>
                </listitem>
            </itemizedlist>
        </section1>
        <section1>
            <title>Corporate transactions</title>
            <para>Corporate transactions are likely to involve a variety of advisers and different types of advice for
                VAT purposes. The following is a general guide.
            </para>
            <section2>
                <title>UK supplies</title>
                <para>The "making of arrangements" for the issue, transfer, receipt of, or any dealing with securities
                    is exempt if made in the UK. The exemption only applies to the party (or parties) that co-ordinates
                    all the components of the transaction and concludes it, for example, an investment or merchant bank.
                    Arranging issues of securities includes offers for sale, rights issues, vendor placings, cash offers
                    and bids with underwritten cash alternatives. Underwriting services provided to a UK issuer are also
                    exempt.
                </para>
                <para>Other parties providing specialist services (for example, reporting accountants and legal
                    advisers) are not generally regarded as "making arrangements" and their services are therefore
                    standard rated.
                </para>
                <para>The services of preparing and issuing advice to investors to reject or accept a takeover bid or
                    offer to purchase shares are also taxable at the standard rate when supplied in the UK.
                </para>
                <para>The supply of general financial or investment advice to a UK client is standard rated.</para>
            </section2>
            <section2>
                <title>Non-UK supplies</title>
                <para>The "making of arrangements" for the issue, transfer, receipt of, or any dealing with securities
                    and underwriting services are:
                </para>
                <itemizedlist>
                    <listitem>
                        <para>Outside the scope of VAT with no input tax credit if the advice is supplied to a client
                            belonging and registered for VAT in another EU member state, who receives the supply for
                            business purposes.
                        </para>
                    </listitem>
                    <listitem>
                        <para>Exempt for a private EC client.</para>
                    </listitem>
                    <listitem>
                        <para>Outside the scope of UK VAT with input tax credit for a non-EC client.</para>
                    </listitem>
                </itemizedlist>
                <para>General legal, accountancy and financial advice is outside the scope of UK VAT but with input tax
                    credit if supplied either to a client belonging in, and registered for VAT in, another EU member
                    state who receives the advice for business purposes or to a client outside the EU.
                </para>
            </section2>
        </section1>
        <section1>
            <title>Glossary</title>
            <para>
                <emphasis role="bold">
                    <emphasis role="italic">Input tax.</emphasis>
                </emphasis>
                Input tax is VAT paid by a taxable person on the supply of taxable goods or services received by him for
                the purposes of his business. This may be offset against any output tax charged by him on the onward
                taxable supply of those goods or services. The difference is payable to Customs &amp; Excise. It is also
                known as input VAT.
            </para>
            <para>
                <emphasis role="bold">
                    <emphasis role="italic">Output tax.</emphasis>
                </emphasis>
                Output tax is VAT charged by a taxable person when supplying taxable goods or services for the purposes
                of his business. It is also known as output VAT.
            </para>
            <para>
                <emphasis role="bold">
                    <emphasis role="italic">Supply chain.</emphasis>
                </emphasis>
                VAT is a cumulative tax on consumption charged at each stage in the chain of the supply of goods or
                services. The supply chain refers to the way in which VAT is charged at each stage by each supplier who
                offsets it against his input tax. The VAT charge is borne by the final consumer at the end of the supply
                chain.
            </para>
        </section1>
        <section1>
            <title>Further Diagrams</title>
            <para>The following diagrams are also available in the PDF version of this article:</para>
            <itemizedlist>
                <listitem>
                    <para>A standard rated supply</para>
                </listitem>
                <listitem>
                    <para>A zero rated supply</para>
                </listitem>
                <listitem>
                    <para>An exempt supply</para>
                </listitem>
            </itemizedlist>
        </section1>
    </fulltext>
</article>