<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!-- Fragment document type declaration subset:
ArborText, Inc., 1988-2001, v.4002
<!DOCTYPE plc PUBLIC "Practical Law Company//DTD PLC Doctype//EN"
 "plc.dtd">
-->
<?Pub Inc?>
<?Pub CX plc(?>
<draftingguide>
    <metadata>
        <identifier>http://www.plcinfo.com/scripts/article.asp?Article_ID=16078</identifier>
        <title>Heads of terms for the grant of a lease: drafting notes</title>
        <abstract>
            <para>Drafting notes for use in conjunction with the PLC precedent Heads of
                terms for the grant of a lease. The notes also deal with the function and
                use of heads of terms generally in property transactions.
            </para>
        </abstract>
    </metadata>
    <fulltext>
        <section1>
            <para>The PLC precedent Heads of terms for the grant of a lease will usually
                be drawn up by the intending landlord's agent or surveyor and can be prepared
                on either the landlord's headed notepaper or that of the landlord's agent.
                They need to be signed by a director of the company for each party to the
                proposed lease.
            </para>
            <para>The heads of terms for the grant of a lease should ideally cover the
                issues set out below. In practice, however, it will be unusual for all these
                points to be addressed and often the more common provisions (such as the tenant's
                right to assign the lease of the whole property with the landlord's consent)
                are omitted on the basis that they are assumed.
            </para>
            <para>The more complete the heads of terms are and the fewer assumptions are
                made, the more likely it is that:
                <itemizedlist>
                    <listitem>
                        <para>The parties
                            will have dealt with all the points of issue before incurring legal costs.
                        </para>
                    </listitem>
                    <listitem>
                        <para>The landlord's solicitor will be able to prepare
                            a first draft lease quickly and easily.
                        </para>
                    </listitem>
                    <listitem>
                        <para>Negotiations will run smoothly and a final form
                            draft lease will be agreed quickly.
                        </para>
                    </listitem>
                    <listitem>
                        <para>The parties will complete the transaction, rather
                            than having to withdraw because of points of issue that cannot be resolved.
                        </para>
                    </listitem>
                </itemizedlist>
            </para>
            <para>It is important that the heads of terms make it clear that the parties
                do not intend to create any legally binding obligations. See Letters of intent
                .
            </para>
        </section1>
        <section1>
            <para>
                <orderedlist>
                    <listitem>
                        <para>Parties</para>
                        <para>
                            <itemizedlist>
                                <listitem>
                                    <para>Tenant's identity. It is important that
                                        it is clear who is to be the tenant, particularly where the tenant is a member
                                        of a group of companies. An unexpected change in the identity of the tenant
                                        can lead to delays because:
                                        <itemizedlist>
                                            <listitem>
                                                <para>there may need to
                                                    be a fresh investigation into the tenant's corporate and financial
                                                    status
                                                </para>
                                            </listitem>
                                            <listitem>
                                                <para>any licences to grant the lease may need to be
                                                    re-negotiated or amended or re-engrossed
                                                </para>
                                            </listitem>
                                            <listitem>
                                                <para>the lease may need to be amended or re-engrossed
                                                </para>
                                            </listitem>
                                            <listitem>
                                                <para>a fresh application may need to be made for any
                                                    court order to exclude the security of tenure provisions under the
                                                    Landlord
                                                    and Tenant Act 1954.
                                                </para>
                                            </listitem>
                                        </itemizedlist>
                                    </para>
                                </listitem>
                                <listitem>
                                    <para>Are the tenant's obligations to be guaranteed and
                                        if so, who will that guarantor be?
                                    </para>
                                </listitem>
                            </itemizedlist>
                        </para>
                    </listitem>
                </orderedlist>
            </para>
        </section1>
    </fulltext>
</draftingguide><?Pub Caret?>
        <?Pub *0000003374 0?>
