<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!-- Fragment document type declaration subset:
ArborText, Inc., 1988-2001, v.4002
<!DOCTYPE plc PUBLIC "Practical Law Company//DTD PLC Doctype//EN"
 "plc.dtd">
-->
<?Pub Inc?>
<?Pub CX plc(?>
<indvprofile>
    <metadata>
        <identifier>http://www.lawdepartment.net/scripts/contact2000.asp?contact_id=31929</identifier>
    </metadata>
    <qualificationdate>1981</qualificationdate>
    <university>
        <para>He obtained his law degree from the Universidad Complutense of Madrid
            in 1981 and completed his education in London, Paris and Brussels later on.
        </para>
    </university>
    <career>
        <para>Mr Hierro became a member of the body of Spanish State Lawyers in 1985
            through public competition. He worked as a State Lawyer in the Ministries
            of Finance and Justice, always in Litigation Areas, and later on in international
            jurisdiction in the ministry of Foreign Affairs, for a total of almost nine
            years. He has been the Director of the Litigation Area of Cuatrecasas Abogados
            since he joined the firm in 1993.
        </para>
    </career>
    <practice>
        <para>Areas of Practice: Antonio Hierro is a senior partner of the law firm
            Cuatrecasas Abogados and is the Director of its Litigation Area, which is
            comprised of more than one hundred and forty lawyers at the present time.
            He has extensive experience representing multinational corporations in EC
            Competition and Telecommunications proceedings, and has represented and defended
            the interests of the State and those of numerous Spanish corporations before
            the European Community Court of Justice on more than fifty occasions over
            the last ten years. During 1991 and 1992, he was the legal advisor of the
            Spanish Government in the negotiation of the Treaty of Maastricht. He also
            specialises in mediation, arbitration and other methods of Alternative Dispute
            Resolution between corporations, and is an arbitrator of the Spanish Civil
            and Mercantile Court of Arbitration (C.I.M.A.) and a counselor of the Madrid
            Court of Arbitration (Official Chamber of Commerce and Industry of Madrid).
        </para>
    </practice>
    <associations>
        <para>Professional Associations: Mr Hierro is a member of the Association
            for the Study of European Law, the International Union of Lawyers (l'Union
            Internationale de Avocats (U.I.A)), and the International Bar Association
            (I.B.A), and has been a member of the Madrid Bar Association (Ilustre Colegio
            de Abogados de Madrid) since 1983.
        </para>
    </associations>
    <publications>
        <para>Mr Hierro is the author of several books, including "Spain and the Treaty
            of Maastricht" (which was elaborated by the members of the Spanish Delegation
            that negotiated the Treaty of Maastricht, edited by Colex, 1994), and is a
            frequent lecturer on arbitration as well as on mediation and methods of Alternative
            Dispute Resolution. In 1993, in recognition of his professional development,
            he was appointed "Spanish Young European Leader" by the French Ministry of
            Foreign Affairs. <?Pub Caret?></para>
    </publications>
</indvprofile>
        <?Pub *0000003004 0?>
