<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!-- Fragment document type declaration subset:
ArborText, Inc., 1988-2001, v.4002
<!DOCTYPE plc PUBLIC "Practical Law Company//DTD PLC Doctype//EN"
 "plc.dtd">
-->
<?Pub Inc?>
<?Pub CX plc(?>
<legalupdate>
    <metadata>
        <title>Right of subrogation</title>
        <abstract>
            <para>The High Court has held that clear words are required to exclude, reduce
                or postpone the right of subrogation.
            </para>
        </abstract>
    </metadata>
    <fulltext>
        <section1>
            <title>Summary</title>
            <para>The High Court has held that clear words are required to exclude, reduce
                or postpone the right of subrogation.
            </para>
        </section1>
        <section1>
            <title>Facts</title>
            <para>OMNIA provided mutual marine insurance to its members. It arranged for
                a bank to guarantee a member's liability to third parties, secured by bonds
                from the claimants for a fee. OMNIA subsequently granted the bank a fixed
                charge over its book debts as a continuing security for its liabilities to
                the bank, until provisional liquidators of OMNIA were appointed. The bank
                appointed receivers under its charge.
            </para>
            <para>Each bond stated that it was "separate from any other security or right
                of indemnity taken in respect of the guarantee from any person, including
                your above named customer". The claimants argued that on payment in full of
                any particular bond, they were entitled to be subrogated to the rights of
                the bank to the security from OMNIA. The bank argued that even assuming that
                such a right would normally arise, it was excluded in this case by the terms
                of the bond.
            </para>
        </section1>
        <section1>
            <title>Decision</title>
            <para>The court held that clear words were required to exclude, reduce or
                postpone the right of subrogation. The requirement to keep the bond separate
                from any other security appeared to be sufficient to cover the position before
                it had been discharged but not to rights arising after and in consequence
                of its payment in full. The Vice Chancellor accepted that it was not clear
                what the draftsman had in mind when inserting the provision, but that the
                uncertainty could not be converted into the clear words which, in his view,
                were required to give rise to the exclusion of postponement.
            </para>
        </section1>
        <section1>
            <title>Case</title>
            <para>
                <emphasis role="italic">L<?Pub Caret1?>iberty Mutual Insurance Co (UK)
                    Limited v HSBC Bank PLC [2001] ALL ER (D) 72.
                </emphasis>
            </para>
        </section1>
    </fulltext>
</legalupdate>
        <?Pub *0000002456 0?>
