<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><!-- Fragment document type declaration subset: Arbortext, Inc., 1988-2005, v.4002 <!DOCTYPE plc PUBLIC "Practical Law Company//DTD PLC Doctype//EN" "plc.dtd">-->
<precedent>
    <atict:info tracking="off" ref="1" xmlns:atict="http://www.arbortext.com/namespace/atict"/>
    <atict:user user="blairn" fullname="Nikki Blair" xmlns:atict="http://www.arbortext.com/namespace/atict"/>
    <atict:user user="carlylh" fullname="Helen Carlyle Lancaster"
                xmlns:atict="http://www.arbortext.com/namespace/atict"/>
    <atict:user user="marrenj" fullname="Jo Marren" xmlns:atict="http://www.arbortext.com/namespace/atict"/>
    <atict:user user="willias" fullname="Sarah Williams" xmlns:atict="http://www.arbortext.com/namespace/atict"/>
    <atict:user user="owens" fullname="Sarah Owens" xmlns:atict="http://www.arbortext.com/namespace/atict"/>
    <metadata></metadata>
    <heading>
        <letterhead partyhead="[Seller or Seller's solicitors]"></letterhead>
        <addressees><!-- insert 'TO' in the output-->
            <addressee>
                <addressline></addressline>
            </addressee>
            <addressee>
                <addressline></addressline>
            </addressee>
        </addressees>
        <date></date>
        <salutation>Dear Sirs</salutation>
        <title>Proposed Agreement to be made between [NAMES OF PARTIES].</title>
    </heading>
    <preamble>
        <para>We refer to the agreement (<defterm>Agreement</defterm>) to be entered into today between [FULL NAME OF
            SELLER] (<defterm>Seller</defterm>) and [FULL NAME OF BUYER] (<defterm>Buyer</defterm>) for the sale and
            purchase of the entire issued share capital of [[TARGET] Limited
            <emphasis role="bold">OR</emphasis>
            the assets and undertaking of the business of [BUSINESS]].
        </para>
        <para>This letter is the Disclosure Letter referred to in the Agreement and constitutes formal disclosure to the
            Buyer for the purposes of the Agreement of the facts and circumstances which are or may be inconsistent with
            the representations, warranties and undertakings referred to in clause [NUMBER] and contained in Schedule
            [NUMBER] of the Agreement (<defterm>Warranties</defterm>) or which otherwise give or may give rise to a
            claim under the Agreement by the Buyer [in respect of the Warranties]. Such facts and circumstances will be
            deemed to qualify the Warranties accordingly.
        </para>
        <para>[This Disclosure Letter is written on behalf of the Seller. The matters and information disclosed or
            referred to in this letter have been supplied to us by or on behalf of the Seller and, accordingly, this
            firm accepts no responsibility or liability whatsoever and howsoever arising from the accuracy, completeness
            or otherwise of all or any part of such matters and information.]
        </para>
        <para>Terms defined in the Agreement shall have the same meaning in this letter. References in this letter to
            paragraph headings and numbers shall, unless the context otherwise requires, be to those headings and
            numbered paragraphs in Schedule [NUMBER] of the Agreement. Such headings and numbering are for convenience
            only and shall not alter the construction of this letter nor in any way limit the effect of any of the
            disclosures, all of which are made against the Warranties as a whole. A disclosure or qualification made by
            reference to any particular paragraph shall be deemed to be made also in respect of any other paragraph to
            which the disclosure or qualification may be applicable.
        </para>
        <para>The disclosure of any matter or document shall not imply any representation, warranty or undertaking not
            expressly given in the Agreement nor shall such disclosure be taken as extending the scope of any of the
            Warranties.
        </para>
    </preamble>
    <operative>
        <clause numbering="none">
            <para>By way of general disclosure, the following matters are disclosed or deemed disclosed to the Buyer:
            </para>
        </clause>
        <clause>
            <para>The contents of the Agreement and all transactions referred to therein.</para>
        </clause>
        <clause>
            <para>[The contents of the Memorandum and Articles of Association of each member of the [TARGET COMPANY
                GROUP] (<defterm>Group</defterm>) and the documents annexed thereto, copies of which have been provided
                to the Buyer.]
            </para>
        </clause>
        <clause>
            <para>All matters which would be revealed by an online search of the file of each member of the Group at the
                Companies Registry at the date hereof.
            </para>
        </clause>
        <clause>
            <para>[The contents of the minute books and other statutory books of each member of the Group, all of which
                have been made available to the Buyer.]
            </para>
        </clause>
        <clause>
            <para>All matters which would be shown by searches at HM Land Registry and HM Land Charges Registry at the
                date of this letter and all matters which would be shown by searches at the local authorities and all
                other public registers relevant to the [Properties<emphasis role="bold">OR</emphasis>real properties
                owned or occupied by members of the Group] carried out at the date of this letter by the Buyer [as a
                buyer of such Properties
                <emphasis role="bold">OR</emphasis>
                as if it were a buyer of such Properties].
            </para>
        </clause>
        <clause>
            <para>All matters contained in the deeds to the Properties, which have been made available to the Buyer.
            </para>
        </clause>
        <clause>
            <para>All matters which would be apparent from an inspection of the Properties at the date of this letter.
            </para>
        </clause>
        <clause>
            <para>All matters contained or referred to in the documents in the bundle of documents annexed to this
                letter, two copies of which have been initialled by the parties thereto for the purposes of
                identification.
            </para>
        </clause>
        <clause>
            <para>Any matters referred to in correspondence between the Seller or its advisers and the Buyer or its
                advisers together with all enclosures attached thereto and all matters referred to in such enclosures.
            </para>
        </clause>
        <clause>
            <para>All matters shown in the audited reports and accounts of [the Seller] [each member of the Group] for
                the financial periods [DATE] to [DATE] [and any matters shown in the management accounts of [the
                Company] [the Seller] for the periods [DATE] to [DATE]].
            </para>
        </clause>
        <clause>
            <para>[All matters disclosed to [the accountants of the Buyer [and/or [OTHERS]] or which ought reasonably to
                have been revealed in the course of the investigation [of the Seller
                <emphasis role="bold">OR</emphasis>
                of the Group] by [such accountants [and/or [OTHERS]] and all matters disclosed in the report produced by
                [such accountants [and/or [OTHERS]] dated [DATE] [on the Business
                <emphasis role="bold">OR</emphasis>
                on the business and affairs of the Group
                <emphasis role="bold">OR</emphasis>
                All matters disclosed in the replies to the pre-contract enquiries raised by the Buyer's solicitors
                dated [DATE] and the replies to those enquiries dated [DATE]].
            </para>
        </clause>
        <clause>
            <para>All matters which would be revealed by a search of the registers and documents maintained by the
                Office of Fair Trading, the Consumer Credit Registry, the Trademarks Registry or the Patent Office in
                respect of each member of the Group as at the date of this letter.
            </para>
        </clause>
        <clause>
            <para>[SPECIFY OTHER DOCUMENTS OR INFORMATION TO BE DEEMED DISCLOSED.]</para>
        </clause>
        <clause>
            <para>All matters of which the Buyer ought reasonably (without having made specific enquiry) to be aware as
                affecting a business similar to the [business carried on by the Company<emphasis role="bold">
                    OR</emphasis>the Business] and all matters which are a matter of public record or within the public
                domain.
            </para>
        </clause>
        <clause numbering="none">
            <para>Where brief particulars only of a matter are set out or referred to in this letter, or a document is
                referred to but not attached, or a reference is made to a particular part only of such document, full
                particulars of the matter and the full contents of the document are deemed to be disclosed and it is
                assumed that the Buyer does not require any further particulars.
            </para>
        </clause>
        <clause numbering="none">
            <para>The following specific disclosures are made in relation to the Warranties:</para>
            <para>[SET OUT SPECIFIC DISCLOSURES.]</para>
        </clause>
        <clause numbering="none">
            <para>Please acknowledge receipt and acceptance of this Disclosure Letter by signing, dating and returning
                the enclosed copy of this letter.
            </para>
        </clause>
    </operative>
    <closing>
        <sincerely>Yours faithfully,</sincerely>
    </closing>
    <signature>
        <clause>
            <para>...<?Pub Caret?>.............................................................</para>
            <para>[Seller or Seller's solicitors]</para>
            <para>We hereby acknowledge receipt and accept the contents of this Disclosure Letter</para>
            <para>Signed .....................................................</para>
            <para>Date ........................................................</para>
        </clause>
    </signature>
</precedent><?Pub *0000008675 0?>