<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><!-- Fragment document type declaration subset: Arbortext, Inc., 1988-2004, v.4002 <!DOCTYPE plc PUBLIC "Practical Law Company//DTD PLC Doctype//EN" "plc.dtd">-->
<precedent
        ><?Pub Caret1?>
    <metadata></metadata>
    <heading>
        <title>Purpose of policy</title>
    </heading>
    <preamble>
        <para>It is [NAME OF EMPLOYER]&#x2019;s policy not to discriminate against its workers on the basis of their
            gender, sexual orientation, marital status, any gender reassignment, race, religion or belief, colour,
            nationality, ethnic or national origin, disability or age, pregnancy or trade union membership or the fact
            that they are a part-time worker or a fixed-term employee. Our workers and applicants for employment shall
            not be disadvantaged by any policies or conditions of service which cannot be justified as necessary for
            operational purposes. [NAME OF EMPLOYER] shall, at all times, strive to work within legislative requirements
            as well as promoting best practice. The board of [NAME OF EMPLOYER]'s long-term aim is that the composition
            of our workforce should reflect that of the community and that all workers should be offered equal
            opportunities to achieve their full potential. This policy, and the measures we take to implement it, have
            been devised on the basis of advice from the relevant government and professional bodies [as well as in
            consultation with appropriate union and/or employee representatives]. We are committed to a programme of
            action to make this policy effective and to bring it to the attention of all workers. The principle of
            non-discrimination and equality of opportunity applies equally to the treatment of visitors, clients,
            customers and suppliers by members of our workforce and also, in some circumstances, ex-employees.
        </para>
        <para>The following paragraphs deal with the specific categories of workers and areas of work which we have
            identified as potentially giving rise to equal opportunities issues and provides more specific guidance on
            the parameters of our policy and approach to equal opportunities.
        </para>
        <para>This policy is for guidance only and shall be provided to all workers, but does not form part of your
            contract of employment.
        </para>
    </preamble>
    <operative>
        <clause>
            <title>To whom does this policy apply?</title>
            <subclause1>
                <para>This policy applies to [NAME OF EMPLOYER]'s employees, whether permanent, temporary, casual,
                    part-time or on fixed-term contracts, to ex-employees, to job applicants and to individuals such as
                    agency staff and consultants [and volunteers] who are not our employees, but who work at the [NAME
                    OF EMPLOYER] (collectively<defterm>workers</defterm>).
                </para>
            </subclause1>
            <subclause1>
                <para>All workers have a duty to act in accordance with this policy, and therefore to treat colleagues
                    with dignity at all times, and not to discriminate against or harass other members of staff, whether
                    junior or senior to them. In some situations, [NAME OF EMPLOYER] may be at risk of being held
                    responsible for the acts of individual members of staff and therefore shall not tolerate any
                    discriminatory practices or behaviour.
                </para>
            </subclause1>
            <subclause1>
                <para>The policy statement in paragraph 1.2 applies equally to the treatment of our clients and
                    suppliers by our workers.
                </para>
            </subclause1>
        </clause>
        <clause>
            <title>Personnel responsible for implementation of policy</title>
            <subclause1>
                <para>The board has overall responsibility for the effective operation of [NAME OF EMPLOYER]'s equal
                    opportunities policy (<defterm>EOP</defterm>) and for ensuring compliance with the relevant
                    statutory framework prohibiting discrimination. The board has delegated day-to-day responsibility
                    for operating the policy and ensuring its maintenance and review to [NAME OF RELEVANT OFFICER].
                </para>
            </subclause1>
            <subclause1>
                <para>Those working at a management level have a specific responsibility to set an appropriate standard
                    of behaviour, to lead by example and to ensure that those they manage adhere to the policy and
                    promote the aims and objectives of [NAME OF EMPLOYER] with regard to equal opportunities. To
                    facilitate this process, managers shall be given training on equal opportunities awareness and equal
                    opportunities recruitment and selection best practice.
                </para>
            </subclause1>
            <subclause1>
                <para>All members of staff are responsible for the success of this policy and must ensure that they
                    familiarise themselves with the policy and act in accordance with its aims and objectives. If you
                    are involved in management or recruitment, or if you have any questions about the content or
                    application of this policy, you should contact the [APPROPRIATE OFFICER] to request training or an
                    information pack.
                </para>
            </subclause1>
        </clause>
        <clause>
            <title>Scope and purpose of policy</title>
            <subclause1>
                <para>[NAME OF EMPLOYER] will not unlawfully discriminate on grounds of gender, sexual orientation,
                    marital status, gender reassignment, race, religion or belief, colour, nationality, ethnic or
                    national origin, disability or age, pregnancy, trade union membership, or part-time or fixed-term
                    status.
                </para>
            </subclause1>
            <subclause1>
                <para>This policy applies to the advertising of jobs and recruitment and selection, to training and
                    development, opportunities for promotion, to conditions of service, benefits and facilities and pay;
                    to health and safety and to conduct at work, to grievance and disciplinary procedures and to
                    termination of employment, including redundancy.
                </para>
            </subclause1>
            <subclause1>
                <para>[NAME OF EMPLOYER] will take appropriate steps to accommodate the requirements of workers'
                    religions, cultures, and domestic responsibilities. Our parental rights policy, and work-life
                    balance policy, should be consulted for specific guidance on our approach to these issues and your
                    entitlements.
                </para>
            </subclause1>
        </clause>
        <clause>
            <title>Forms of discrimination</title>
            <subclause1>
                <para>Discrimination may be direct or indirect and it may occur intentionally or unintentionally. Direct
                    discrimination occurs where someone is put at a disadvantage for a reason related to one or more of
                    the grounds set out in paragraph 3.1. For example, rejecting an applicant of one race because it is
                    considered they would not "fit in" on the grounds of their race could be direct discrimination.
                    Indirect discrimination occurs where an individual is subject to an unjustified provision, criterion
                    or practice which puts them at a particular disadvantage because of, for example, their sex or race.
                    For example, a height requirement would be likely to eliminate proportionately more women than men.
                    If this criteria cannot be objectively justified for a reason unconnected with sex, it would be
                    indirectly discriminatory on the grounds of sex. Discrimination also includes victimisation (less
                    favourable treatment because of action taken to assert legal rights against discrimination or to
                    assist a colleague in that regard) and harassment (see [NAME OF EMPLOYER]'s anti-harassment policy).
                </para>
            </subclause1>
        </clause>
        <clause>
            <title>Recruitment and selection</title>
            <subclause1>
                <para>[NAME OF EMPLOYER] aims to ensure that no job applicant receives less favourable treatment on any
                    of the unlawful grounds listed in paragraph 3.1. Recruitment procedures will be reviewed regularly
                    to ensure that individuals are treated on the basis of their relevant merits and abilities and that
                    sufficiently diverse sectors of the community are reached. Job selection criteria are regularly
                    reviewed to ensure that they are justifiable on non-discriminatory grounds as being essential for
                    the effective performance of the job.
                </para>
            </subclause1>
            <subclause1>
                <para>[NAME OF EMPLOYER] shall take steps to ensure that knowledge of vacancies reaches a wide labour
                    market and, where relevant, groups under-represented in [NAME OF EMPLOYER]. Where appropriate, use
                    may be made of lawful exemptions to recruit suitably-qualified people to cater for the special needs
                    of particular groups. Vacancy advertisements shall include an appropriate short statement on our
                    equal opportunities policy and a copy of this policy shall be sent to those who enquire about
                    vacancies.
                </para>
            </subclause1>
            <subclause1>
                <para>To ensure that this policy is operating effectively with respect to recruitment and selection and
                    the other areas identified in paragraph 3.2, and to identify those sections of the local community
                    which may be under-represented in employment, [NAME OF EMPLOYER] monitors applicants' racial
                    origins, gender, disability, [sexual orientation and religion] [and age] as part of the recruitment
                    procedure. We also maintain records of this data [in an anonymised format] solely for the purposes
                    stated in this policy. Ongoing monitoring and regular analysis of the data provide the basis for
                    taking appropriate positive steps to eliminate unlawful direct and indirect discrimination and
                    implement this policy.
                </para>
            </subclause1>
        </clause>
        <clause>
            <title>Staff training and promotion and conditions of service</title>
            <subclause1>
                <para>Staff training needs shall be identified through regular staff appraisals. All workers will be
                    given an equal opportunity and access to training to enable them to progress within the
                    organisation. All promotion decisions shall be made on the basis of merit.
                </para>
            </subclause1>
            <subclause1>
                <para>The composition and movement of workers at different levels shall be regularly monitored to ensure
                    equality of opportunity at all levels of the organisation. Where appropriate, steps will be taken to
                    identify and remove unnecessary or unjustifiable barriers and to provide appropriate facilities and
                    conditions of service to meet the special needs of disadvantaged or under-represented groups.
                </para>
            </subclause1>
            <subclause1>
                <para>Our conditions of service, benefits and facilities will be reviewed regularly to ensure that they
                    are available to all workers who should have access to them and that there are no unlawful obstacles
                    to accessing them. This includes pay, bonus criteria, policies and all benefits offered, such as
                    private medical insurance, permanent health insurance (PHI) insurance and gym membership.
                </para>
            </subclause1>
        </clause>
        <clause>
            <title>Termination of employment</title>
            <subclause1>
                <para>We will monitor redundancy criteria and procedures to ensure that they are fair and objective and
                    do not directly or indirectly discriminate against employees.
                </para>
            </subclause1>
            <subclause1>
                <para>We will also ensure that disciplinary procedures are carried out fairly and uniformly for all
                    workers, whether they result in the giving of disciplinary warnings, dismissal or other disciplinary
                    action.
                </para>
            </subclause1>
        </clause>
        <clause>
            <title>Disability discrimination</title>
            <subclause1>
                <para>If you are disabled, or become disabled in the course of your employment with us, you are
                    encouraged to tell us about your condition. This is to enable us to support you as much as possible.
                    You may also wish to advise your [line manager
                    <emphasis role="bold">OR</emphasis>
                    the personnel department] of any reasonable adjustments to your working conditions or the duties of
                    your job which you consider to be necessary, or which would assist you in the performance of your
                    duties. Your [line manager
                    <emphasis role="bold">OR</emphasis>
                    the personnel department] may wish to consult with you and with your medical adviser(s) about
                    possible reasonable adjustments. Careful consideration will be given to any such proposals and they
                    will be accommodated where possible and proportionate to the needs of your job. Nevertheless, there
                    may be circumstances where it will not be reasonable for us to accommodate the suggested adjustments
                    and we will ensure that we provide you with information as to the basis of our decision not to make
                    any adjustments.
                </para>
            </subclause1>
            <subclause1>
                <para>[NAME OF EMPLOYER] carried out an access audit of its premises in advance of Part 3 of the
                    Disability Discrimination Act 1995 coming into force in October 2004 and shall continue to monitor
                    the physical features of its premises to consider whether they place disabled workers, job
                    applicants or service users at a substantial disadvantage compared to other workers. Where possible
                    and proportionate, [NAME OF EMPLOYER] will take steps to improve access for disabled workers and
                    service users.
                </para>
            </subclause1>
        </clause>
        <clause>
            <title>Fixed-term employees [and agency and temporary workers]</title>
            <subclause1>
                <para>We will monitor our use of fixed-term employees and agency workers, and their conditions of
                    service, to ensure that they are being offered appropriate access to benefits, training, promotion
                    and permanent employment opportunities. We will, where relevant, monitor their progress within [NAME
                    OF EMPLOYER] to ensure that they are accessing permanent vacancies.
                </para>
            </subclause1>
        </clause>
        <clause>
            <title>Part-time workers</title>
            <subclause1>
                <para>[NAME OF EMPLOYER] will monitor the conditions of service of part-time employees and their
                    progression within [NAME OF EMPLOYER] to ensure that they are being offered appropriate access to
                    benefits and training and promotion opportunities. We will also ensure requests to alter working
                    hours are dealt with appropriately under our [flexible working procedure].
                </para>
            </subclause1>
        </clause>
        <clause>
            <title>Breaches of the policy</title>
            <subclause1>
                <para>If you believe that you may have been disadvantaged on any of the unlawful grounds listed at
                    paragraph 3.1, you are encouraged to raise the matter through [NAME OF EMPLOYER]'s grievance
                    procedure. If you believe that you may have been harassed on any of the unlawful grounds listed at
                    paragraph 3.1, you are encouraged to raise the matter through the our [anti-harassment policy].
                    Allegations regarding potential breaches of this policy will be treated in confidence and
                    investigated in accordance with the relevant procedure. Workers who make such allegations in good
                    faith will not be victimised or treated less favourably as a result. False allegations of a breach
                    in this policy which are found to have been made in bad faith will, however, be dealt with under our
                    [disciplinary procedure].
                </para>
            </subclause1>
            <subclause1>
                <para>If, after investigation, you are proven to have harassed any other worker on the grounds of sex,
                    marital status, sexual orientation, religion or belief, race, disability or age or otherwise act in
                    breach of this policy, you will be subject to disciplinary action. In serious cases, such behaviour
                    may constitute gross misconduct and, as such, may result in summary dismissal. [NAME OF EMPLOYER]
                    will always take a strict approach to serious breaches of this policy.
                </para>
            </subclause1>
            <subclause1>
                <para>As this policy applies equally to [NAME OF EMPLOYER] workers' relations with clients and
                    suppliers, if, after investigation, you are proven to have discriminated against or harassed a
                    client or supplier you will also be subject to disciplinary action.
                </para>
            </subclause1>
        </clause>
        <clause>
            <title>Monitoring and revision of policy</title>
            <subclause1>
                <para>This policy is reviewed annually by the [NAME OF RELEVANT OFFICER] in consultation with the [UNION
                    OR EMPLOYEE CONSULTATIVE BODY]. Recommendations for any amendments are reported to the audit
                    committee and board.
                </para>
                <para>Policy last updated [DATE].</para>
            </subclause1>
            <subclause1>
                <para>We will regularly monitor the effectiveness of this policy to ensure it is achieving the
                    objectives stated in the EOP statement by monitoring the composition of job applicants and the
                    benefits and career progression of its workers.
                </para>
            </subclause1>
            <subclause1>
                <para>[NAME OF EMPLOYER] is committed to providing relevant training for all staff on their
                    responsibilities and duties under this policy.
                </para>
            </subclause1>
        </clause>
    </operative>
</precedent><?Pub *0000015880 0?>