<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!-- Fragment document type declaration subset:
ArborText, Inc., 1988-2001, v.4002
<!DOCTYPE plc PUBLIC "Practical Law Company//DTD PLC Doctype//EN"
 "plc.dtd">
-->
<?Pub Inc?>
<?Pub CX plc(?>
<practicenote>
    <metadata>
        <title>Jo<?Pub Caret?>int and several liability</title>
        <abstract>
            <para>This is a note on joint and several liability. If more than one person
                takes on liability for the same obligation, the liability of each person may
                be joint or several or joint and several. See also:
            </para>
        </abstract>
        <jurisdiction>England, Wales</jurisdiction>
    </metadata>
    <fulltext>
        <section1>
            <para>Where more than one person takes on an obligation, their liability may
                be
                <itemizedlist>
                    <listitem>
                        <para>Joint, or</para>
                    </listitem>
                    <listitem>
                        <para>Several, or</para>
                    </listitem>
                    <listitem>
                        <para>Joint and several.</para>
                    </listitem>
                </itemizedlist>
            </para>
            <para>Where a party to a contract or deed is made up of more than one person,
                the nature of the liability of that party will usually be expressly stated.
                The document will often also deal with the liability of successors in title
                to the original parties if they are made up of more than one person.
            </para>
            <para>Where a document is silent as to the nature of the liability, then it
                will be a matter of construction. In general there will be joint liability
                if two or more people covenant in the same document that they or any one of
                them will do something or if they covenant generally without using any words
                of severance.
            </para>
            <para>Illustration:</para>
            <para>
                <emphasis>If A and B jointly agree to pay X &pound;1,000</emphasis>
                then
                X is entitled to &pound;1,000 and may claim the whole amount from either A
                or B. There is only one obligation. Payment of &pound;1,000 by A will discharge
                the liability of both A and B. If X releases A from the obligation to pay,
                then B will also be released.
            </para>
            <para>
                <emphasis>If A and B severally agree to pay X &pound;1,000</emphasis>
                then
                X is entitled to &pound;1,000 from A and a further &pound;1,000 from B. There
                are in effect two separate contracts: one between A and X, and one between
                B and X. If A pays &pound;1,000, B will still owe &pound;1,000.
            </para>
            <para>Sometimes, however, the liability will not be cumulative. This can occur
                in a property context where an original tenant and later an assignee separately
                covenant with the landlord to pay the rent. The landlord is only entitled
                to the rent once.
            </para>
            <para>
                <emphasis>If A and B jointly and severally agree to pay X &pound;1,000</emphasis>
                then
                X is entitled to &pound;1000 and may claim the whole of it from either A or
                B. The nature of a joint and several obligation is that:
                <orderedlist>
                    <listitem>
                        <para>A and B jointly promise to pay X &pound;1,000;</para>
                    </listitem>
                    <listitem>
                        <para>A promises that X will be paid &pound;1,000 by either A or
                            B; and
                        </para>
                    </listitem>
                    <listitem>
                        <para>B promises that X will be paid &pound;1,000 by either A or
                            B.
                        </para>
                    </listitem>
                </orderedlist>
            </para>
            <para>There is a joint obligation and separate obligations. However, the obligations
                are not cumulative and X is entitled to &pound;1,000 in total, not &pound;3,000.
                Payment of &pound;1,000 by A will discharge the liability of A and B. Despite
                the separate promises, some of the technical rules on the discharge of joint
                contractors also apply to joint and several contractors.
            </para>
        </section1>
        <section1>
            <title>Discharge of liability</title>
            <para>There are a number of complex rules that affect the discharge of joint
                contractors and, somewhat illogically, some of these also apply to joint and
                several contractors. For example, the release of one joint or joint and several
                contractor will release the others. Similarly accord and satisfaction with
                one joint or joint and several contractor will discharge the others. However,
                the application of these rules depends upon the exact formulation and expression
                of what the covenantee/creditor purports to do. For example, sometimes a 'release'
                of one joint or joint and several contractor will be construed as an agreement
                not to sue and so preserve the position against the other(s); or the terms
                of an accord and satisfaction with one joint or joint and several contractor
                may reserve the covenantee/creditor&rsquo;s rights against the other(s).
            </para>
        </section1>
        <section1>
            <title>Section 13, Landlord and Tenant (Covenants) Act 1995</title>
            <para>This provides that:
                <itemizedlist>
                    <listitem>
                        <para>Where 'in consequence
                            of' the 1995 Act, two or more persons become bound by the same covenant, then
                            their liability will be joint and several.
                        </para>
                    </listitem>
                    <listitem>
                        <para>Where 'by virtue of' the 1995 Act, two or more
                            persons are jointly and severally liable and one of those persons is released
                            from the covenant, the release does not extend to any other of those persons.
                            This is subject to section 24(2) which deals with the release (principally)
                            of guarantors.
                        </para>
                    </listitem>
                </itemizedlist>
            </para>
            <para>The Civil Liability (Contribution) Act 1978 will apply as regards one
                person seeking a contribution from another where they are jointly and severally
                liable by virtue of the 1995 Act.
            </para>
        </section1>
        <section1>
            <title>Property documents</title>
            <para>Condition 1.2 of both the Standard Conditions of Sale (3rd edition)
                and of the Standard Commercial Property Conditions (1st Edition) state that
                'if there is more than one seller or more than one buyer, the obligations
                which they undertake can be enforced against them all jointly or against each
                individually'. This would need clarification and expansion where, for example,
                there were many sellers each selling a different property.
            </para>
        </section1>
        <section1>
            <title>Further reading</title>
            <para>For further reading see Chitty, Volume I, chapters 17 and 25.</para>
        </section1>
    </fulltext>
</practicenote>
        <?Pub *0000005885 0?>
