<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><!-- Fragment document type declaration subset: Arbortext, Inc., 1988-2005, v.4002 <!DOCTYPE plc PUBLIC "Practical Law Company//DTD PLC Doctype//EN" "plc.dtd">-->
<precedent xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
    <metadata>
        <revhistory>
            <revision>
                <revtitle>Resource created</revtitle>
                <date>[Insert date (eg 30 Sep 2006)]</date>
                <author>[Insert author name]</author>
                <revdescription>
                    <section1>
                        <para>[Insert details of change]</para>
                    </section1>
                </revdescription>
            </revision>
        </revhistory>
    </metadata>
    <preamble>
        <title>Nondisclosure Agreement</title>
        <para>This Nondisclosure Agreement (<defterm>Agreement</defterm>) effective _________________, 2007 (<defterm>
            Effective Date</defterm>), is by and between XXXXXX, LLC, a Delaware limited liability company (<defterm>
            Disclosing Party</defterm>), and _________________, a ____________________ (<defterm>Receiving
            Party</defterm>). Disclosing Party and Receiving Party may be referred to herein individually as a
            <defterm>Party</defterm>
            or collectively as the<defterm>Parties</defterm>.
        </para>
        <para>WHEREAS, the Parties desire to enter into discussions regarding certain business opportunities and such
            discussions may involve the exchange of data, financial information, trade secrets, or other information or
            intellectual property considered confidential or proprietary by Disclosing Party or its Affiliates (defined
            herein) which Disclosing Party desires to protect as confidential information (<defterm>Potential
                Transaction</defterm>); and
        </para>
        <para>WHEREAS, Disclosing Party wishes to protect its respective proprietary and confidential information and
            trade secrets.
        </para>
        <para>NOW, THEREFORE, in consideration of the mutual covenants, terms and conditions set forth herein, and for
            other good and valuable consideration, the receipt and sufficiency of which are hereby acknowledged, the
            parties agree as follows:
        </para>
    </preamble>
    <operative xrefname="section"><?Pub Caret?>
        <clause id="a315425">
            <para>Disclosing Party may disclose to Receiving Party non-public verbal, written, electronic or graphic
                data and information which the Disclosing Party considers proprietary and confidential, which may
                contain trade secrets, and which may include the information or data of an Affiliate of the Disclosing
                Party that is considered proprietary and confidential or may contain trade secrets (<defterm>
                    Confidential Information</defterm>). The Parties agree that all Confidential Information provided by
                or on behalf of Disclosing Party to Receiving Party, or to which Receiving Party is given access by or
                on behalf of Disclosing Party, whether in correspondence or other exchange of documents, during any
                interviews, discussions, meetings, and other interactions involving Disclosing Party, Receiving Party,
                their respective directors, officers, employees or agents, regardless of the form in which it is
                provided or exists, is considered by the Disclosing Party to be proprietary, confidential and to contain
                trade secrets and that such Confidential Information has economic value to the Disclosing Party.
                Accordingly, the Parties agree that all such Confidential Information shall be treated by the Receiving
                Party as confidential.
            </para>
        </clause>
        <clause id="a517038">
            <para>With respect to Confidential Information:</para>
            <subclause1 id="a501515">
                <subclause2 id="a721451">
                    <para>The Receiving Party shall use the Confidential Information only for the purpose of discussing
                        and negotiating the Potential Transaction with the Disclosing Party (<defterm>Authorized
                            Purpose</defterm>);
                    </para>
                </subclause2>
                <subclause2 id="a750456">
                    <para>The Receiving Party shall not disclose the Confidential Information to any other Person
                        (except to the Receiving Party&#x2019;s employees, including employees of its Affiliates, and
                        advisors, counsel or contractors (collectively, the Receiving Party&#x2019;s "Representatives")
                        who have a need to know such Confidential Information in connection with the Authorized Purpose,
                        and in accordance with this Agreement) without the prior written consent of the Disclosing
                        Party; and
                    </para>
                </subclause2>
                <subclause2 id="a210912">
                    <para>The Receiving Party shall safeguard the Confidential Information with the same degree of care
                        to avoid unauthorized disclosure as it uses to protect its own confidential and proprietary
                        information and trade secrets, but in no case less than a reasonable degree of care.
                    </para>
                </subclause2>
            </subclause1>
        </clause>
        <clause id="a336868">
            <para>The following information shall not constitute Confidential Information hereunder:</para>
            <subclause1 id="a221648">
                <subclause2 id="a740878">
                    <para>Information that is or becomes available to the public through no breach of this Agreement;
                    </para>
                </subclause2>
                <subclause2 id="a251363">
                    <para>Information that is received by the Receiving Party from a third party; provided that the
                        source of such information was not known by the Receiving Party to be bound by a confidentiality
                        agreement with, or other contractual, legal or fiduciary obligation of confidentiality to, the
                        Disclosing Party with respect to such information;
                    </para>
                </subclause2>
                <subclause2 id="a985488">
                    <para>Information that was already in the Receiving Party&#x2019;s possession prior to its
                        disclosure hereunder; provided that the source of such information was not known by the
                        Receiving Party to be bound by a confidentiality agreement with, or other contractual, legal or
                        fiduciary obligation of confidentiality to, the Disclosing Party with respect to such
                        information;
                    </para>
                </subclause2>
                <subclause2 id="a290437">
                    <para>Information that is independently developed by the Receiving Party without the use of any
                        Confidential Information of the Disclosing Party;
                    </para>
                </subclause2>
                <subclause2 id="a308683">
                    <para>Information that is approved for release by written authorization of the Disclosing Party, but
                        only to the extent of and subject to such conditions as may be imposed in such written
                        authorization;
                    </para>
                </subclause2>
                <subclause2 id="a108012">
                    <para>Information that is required by law or regulation to be disclosed, but only in accordance with
                        <plcxlink>
                            <xlink:locator xlink:href="#a625023" xlink:role="xref"
                                           xlink:title="clause 5 - If the Receiving Party or">clause 5
                                <xref link="a625023"></xref>
                            </xlink:locator>
                        </plcxlink>
                        ; and
                    </para>
                </subclause2>
                <subclause2 id="a942981">
                    <para>Information that is disclosed in response to a valid order of a court or other governmental
                        body of the United States or any political subdivisions thereof, but only in accordance with
                        <plcxlink>
                            <xlink:locator xlink:href="#a625023" xlink:role="xref"
                                           xlink:title="clause 5 - If the Receiving Party or">clause 5
                                <xref link="a625023"></xref>
                            </xlink:locator>
                        </plcxlink>
                        .
                    </para>
                </subclause2>
            </subclause1>
        </clause>
        <clause id="a625023">
            <para>If the Receiving Party or any of its Representatives are requested or required (by oral questions,
                interrogatories, requests for information or documents in legal proceedings or by the Securities and
                Exchange Commission, subpoena, civil investigative demand or other similar process or pursuant to
                applicable laws or regulations) to disclose any of the Disclosing Party&#x2019;s Confidential
                Information, the Receiving Party shall provide the Disclosing Party with prompt written notice of any
                such request or requirement so that the Disclosing Party may seek, at its sole expense, a protective
                order or other appropriate remedy and/or waive compliance with the provisions of this Agreement. If, in
                the absence of a protective order or other remedy or the receipt of a waiver by the Disclosing Party,
                the Receiving Party or any of its Representatives are nonetheless legally compelled to make any such
                disclosure of the Disclosing Party&#x2019;s Confidential Information to any Person, the Disclosing Party
                or its Representative may, without liability hereunder, disclose to such Person only that portion of the
                Disclosing Party&#x2019;s Confidential Information that on the advice of its counsel is legally required
                to be disclosed, provided that the Receiving Party or its Representative making such disclosing will use
                its reasonable efforts to assist the Disclosing Party, at the Disclosing Party&#x2019;s expense, in
                obtaining an appropriate protective order or other reliable assurance that confidential treatment will
                be accorded the Disclosing Party&#x2019;s Confidential Information by such Person to whom disclosure is
                to be made.
            </para>
        </clause>
        <clause>
            <para>Confidential Information of the Disclosing Party, including all copies thereof, shall remain the
                property of the Disclosing Party (or its applicable Affiliate). The Receiving Party shall either return
                or destroy all Confidential Information of the Disclosing Party received in tangible form (including any
                copies thereof), to the Disclosing Party within fifteen (15) business days following termination of this
                Agreement, unless the Disclosing Party requests, in writing, the return or destruction of the
                Confidential Information on an earlier date. The Receiving Party shall also, within five (5) business
                days following its receipt of a written request from the Disclosing Party, certify in writing that it
                has satisfied its obligations under
                <plcxlink>
                    <xlink:locator xlink:href="#a517038" xlink:role="xref"
                                   xlink:title="clause 3 - 3.	With respect to Confid">clause 3
                        <xref link="a517038"></xref>
                    </xlink:locator>
                </plcxlink>
                of this Agreement with respect to the Disclosing Party&#x2019;s Confidential Information.
            </para>
        </clause>
        <clause>
            <para>Lots of other fun stuff</para>
        </clause>
    </operative>
    <signature pagebreak="true" signaturemessage="yes">
        <clause id="a254050">
            <para>IN WITNESS WHEREOF, the Parties have executed this Agreement to be effective as of the date first
                above written.
            </para>
            <table frame="none" pgwide="1">
                <tgroup cols="2">
                    <colspec colname="col1"/>
                    <colspec colname="col2"/>
                    <tbody>
                        <row>
                            <entry></entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>Company Name</para>
                                <para></para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry></entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>By_____________________</para>
                                <para></para>
                                <para>Name:</para>
                                <para>Title:</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                    </tbody>
                </tgroup>
            </table>
        </clause>
    </signature>
</precedent><?Pub *0000010133 0?>