<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><!-- Fragment document type declaration subset: Arbortext, Inc., 1988-2004, v.4002 <!DOCTYPE plc PUBLIC "Practical Law Company//DTD PLC Doctype//EN" "plc.dtd">-->
<precedent>
    <metadata>
        <revhistory>
            <revision>
                <revtitle>Resource created</revtitle>
                <date>[Insert date (eg 30 Sep 2006)]</date>
                <author>[Insert author name]</author>
                <revdescription>
                    <section1>
                        <para>[Insert details of change]</para>
                    </section1>
                </revdescription>
            </revision>
        </revhistory>
    </metadata>
    <heading>
        <letterhead>
            <title>[LETTERHEAD]</title>
        </letterhead>
        <para>[DATE]</para>
        <para>[METHOD OF DELIVERY]</para>
        <para>[NAME AND ADDRESS]</para>
        <para></para>
        <para>Dear Sirs:</para>
        <para>[Re: XXXXXX]</para>
    </heading>
    <preamble>
        <para>[LEGAL NAME OF BUYER] ("Buyer") sets out in this letter agreement (the "Agreement") certain
            representations, warranties and agreements relating to the proposed purchase by Buyer, subject to the terms
            and conditions set forth below, from [LEGAL NAME OF SELLER] ("Seller" and, together with Buyer, the
            "Parties") of [QUANTITY] shares of [DESCRIPTION OF SECURITIES, INCLUDING NAME OF ISSUER AND CLASS], par
            value $[x] per share (the "Securities") in a transaction subject to the terms and conditions set forth below
            (hereinafter referred to as the "Transaction").
        </para>
    </preamble>
    <operative properties="ussfawithtitles" xrefname="section">
        <clause>
            <title>Purchase Price</title>
            <para>The Buyer and Seller agree that the consideration payable for the Securities is $[x], payable [in the
                manner agreed by the Parties]. The Seller will deliver the Securities to the Buyer [in the manner agreed
                by the Parties]. The Transaction will close as soon as practicable after the full execution of this
                letter agreement by the Parties, but not later than [NUMBER OF DAYS] business days after the full
                execution of this letter agreement.
            </para>
        </clause>
        <clause>
            <title>Seller Acknowledgments and Agreements</title>
            <para>Seller acknowledges and agrees as follows:</para>
            <subclause1>
                <subclause2>
                    <para>Seller has received and carefully reviewed the Annual Report of the [Issuer] ("Issuer") on
                        Form 10-K for the fiscal year ended [20XX] and all subsequent public filings of the Issuer with
                        the Securities and Exchange Commission, other publicly available information regarding the
                        Issuer, and such other information that it and its advisers deem necessary to make its decision
                        to enter into the Transaction;
                    </para>
                </subclause2>
                <subclause2>
                    <para>Seller has made its own decision to consummate the Transaction based on its own independent
                        review and consultations with such investment, legal, tax, accounting and other advisers as it
                        deemed necessary. Seller has made its own decision concerning the Transaction without reliance
                        on any representation or warranty of, or advice from, the Buyer;
                    </para>
                </subclause2>
                <subclause2>
                    <para>Seller acknowledges and understands that Buyer [and its officers and affiliates] possess[es]
                        material nonpublic information not known to Seller that may impact the value of the Securities
                        (the<defterm>Information</defterm>), that Buyer is unable to disclose to Seller [, including
                        without limitation, (i) information received by principals and employees of the Buyer in their
                        capacities as directors, officers, significant stockholders and/or affiliates of Issuer, (ii)
                        information otherwise received from the Issuer on a confidential basis, and (iii) information
                        received on a privileged basis from the attorneys and financial advisers representing the Issuer
                        and its Board of Directors]. Seller understands, based on its experience, the disadvantage to
                        which Seller is subject due to the disparity of information between the Buyer and the Seller.
                        Notwithstanding this, Seller has deemed it appropriate to engage in the Transaction;
                    </para>
                </subclause2>
            </subclause1>
        </clause>
        <clause>
            <title>Notice Requirements</title>
            <para>All notices, requests, consents, claims, demands, waivers and other communications hereunder shall be
                in writing and shall be deemed to have been given (a) when delivered by hand (with written confirmation
                of receipt); (b) when received by the addressee if sent by a nationally recognized overnight courier
                (receipt requested); (c) on the date sent by facsimile or e-mail of a PDF document (with confirmation of
                transmission) if sent during normal business hours of the recipient, and on the next Business Day if
                sent after normal business hours of the recipient; or (d) on the [third] day after the date mailed, by
                certified or registered mail, return receipt requested, postage prepaid. Such communications must be
                sent to the respective parties at the addresses indicated below (or at such other address for a party as
                shall be specified in a notice given in accordance with this Section [??]).
            </para>
            <table>
                <tgroup cols="2">
                    <colspec colname="col1"/>
                    <colspec colname="col2"/>
                    <tbody>
                        <row>
                            <entry>
                                <para>If to the Company:</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>[COMPANY ADDRESS]</para>
                                <para>Facsimile: [FAX NUMBER]</para>
                                <para>E-mail: [E-MAIL ADDRESS]</para>
                                <para>Attention: [TITLE OF OFFICER TO RECEIVE NOTICES]</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry>
                                <para>with a copy to:</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>[COMPANY LAW FIRM]</para>
                                <para>Facsimile: [FAX NUMBER]</para>
                                <para>E-mail: [E-MAIL ADDRESS]</para>
                                <para>Attention: [ATTORNEY NAME]</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                    </tbody>
                </tgroup>
            </table>
        </clause>
        <clause>
            <title>Other Agreements of the Parties</title>
            <para>This letter agreement (i) shall constitute the binding agreement of the Parties with respect to the
                subject matter hereof and shall constitute the entire agreement of the parties with respect to the
                subject matter hereof, and (ii) may be executed by facsimile transmission of executed counterparts,
                which together shall constitute one and the same agreement. The Transaction shall be subject to the laws
                of the State of [NAME OF STATE], without reference to conflict of laws principles.
            </para>
            <para>Please sign a copy of this letter agreement and return a copy by facsimile and the original by
                [mail/courier] to the undersigned. If we do not receive your signed counterpart of this letter agreement
                by the close of business [MONTH][DAY],[YEAR], Buyer's offer shall be rescinded and this letter agreement
                shall immediately terminate and be of no further effect.
            </para>
        </clause>
    </operative>
    <signature pagebreak="true" signaturemessage="yes">
        <clause>
            <para>IN WITNESS WHEREOF, the parties hereto have executed this Agreement as of the date first above
                written.
            </para>
            <table frame="none" pgwide="1">
                <tgroup cols="2">
                    <colspec colname="col1" colwidth="50%"/>
                    <colspec colname="col2" colwidth="50%"/>
                    <tbody>
                        <row>
                            <entry></entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>Very truly yours,</para>
                                <para></para>
                                <para>[BUYER]</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry></entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para></para>
                                <para>By:___________________________</para>
                                <para>[Name:]</para>
                                <para>[Title:]</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                    </tbody>
                </tgroup>
            </table>
            <table frame="none" pgwide="1">
                <tgroup cols="2">
                    <colspec colname="col1"/>
                    <colspec colname="col2"/>
                    <tbody>
                        <row>
                            <entry>
                                <para>[Agreed to and accepted: - Optional]</para>
                                <para>[SELLER]</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry></entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry>
                                <para>By:_______________________________</para>
                                <para>[Name:]</para>
                                <para>[Title:]</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry></entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry nameend="col2" namest="col1">
                                <para>cc [ALTERNATE PAYEE NAME], Alternate Payee</para>
                                <para>[PARTICIPANT NAME], Participant</para>
                                <para>[ATTORNEY], for Alternate Payee</para>
                                <para>[ATTORNEY], for Participant</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                    </tbody>
                </tgroup>
            </table>
        </clause>
    </signature>
    <appendix>
        <para>[[Schedule/Exhibit/attachments title]</para>
        <para>[text/tables for schedule]]</para>
        <table>
            <tgroup cols="2">
                <colspec colname="col1"/>
                <colspec colname="col2"/>
                <tbody>
                    <row>
                        <entry>
                            <para>Trademark licence table</para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry></entry>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <entry></entry>
                        <entry></entry>
                    </row>
                </tbody>
            </tgroup>
        </table>
    </appendix>
</precedent>